var chapters = [
  { chapter: 1, title: "Overview of International Business" },
  { chapter: 2, title: "Fundamentals of International Finance" },
  { chapter: 3, title: "International Foreign Exchange Markets" },
  { chapter: 4, title: "Foreign Exchange Management in India" },
  { chapter: 5, title: "Foreign Exchange Quotations" },
  { chapter: 6, title: "Foreign Exchange Calculations" },
  { chapter: 7, title: "Exchange Rate Regimes" },
  { chapter: 8, title: "Euro Currency Market" },
  { chapter: 9, title: "International Equity Markets" },
  { chapter: 10, title: "Risk Management and Derivatives" },
  { chapter: 11, title: "International Institutions" },
  //   { chapter: 12, title: "Appendix" },
];

var allQuestionAnswers = [
  {
    question:
      "One of the most significant trends in ______ has been the rapid and sustained growth of international business in the world.",
    options: [
      "The last century",
      "Past two decades",
      "Last three years",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Past two decades",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The term International Business emerged from what was earlier known as ______ marketing.",
    options: ["Import", "Domestic", "Export", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Export",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ account for large share in international business, but substantial liberalization is occurring outside _______ as well.",
    options: ["GATT/WTO", "UNO/UNESCO", "IDFC/IBRD", "None of the above"],
    answer: "GATT/WTO",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "These enterprises link their resources and objectives with world market opportunities and have been powerful force driving globalization targets.",
    options: ["M&A", "Limited Companies", "MNCs", "All of the above"],
    answer: "MNCs",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ cost of technology has been a very important facilitating factor in globalization.",
    options: ["Falling", "Structured", "Increasing", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Increasing",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To recoup such high product development costs typically in _____ industry, an international market is absolutely essential.",
    options: ["Automobile", "Cement", "Pharmaceuticals", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Pharmaceuticals",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The two most important determinants of demand are the _________ which are better achieved when the firm has international  operations.",
    options: [
      "Market and elasticity",
      "Quality and price",
      "Sourcing and its reliability",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Quality and price",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The _____ growth of the developed economies, prompts firms of developed countries to turn to the expanding markets,elsewhere.",
    options: ["Fast", "High", "Slow", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Slow",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The proliferation of regional integration schemes, like the European Union (EC), SAARC, etc._____ the business internationalization trend.",
    options: ["Restricts", "Regulates", "Fosters", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Fosters",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Leverage is big advantage that a company enjoys by virtue of the fact that it conducts business in",
    options: [
      "A country with stagnant market",
      "A country with large market",
      "More than one country",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "More than one country",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "________ forced Ciba-Geigy to concentrate on overseas markets and establish manufacturing facilities in foreign countries including India.",
    options: [
      "Limited Home Market",
      "Higher Rate of Profit",
      "Regional Integration",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Limited Home Market",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Most of the US based and Europe based companies located their manufacturing facilities in Saudi Arabia, Qatar, Oman, Iran and other middle-east countries due to the availability of cheap",
    options: ["Skills", "Market", "Raw materials", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Raw materials",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Software, high technology and telecommunications companies located their operations in India mainly because of availability of cheap",
    options: ["Skills", "Market", "Raw materials", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Skills",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Tariffs and quotas are there in developing as well as developed economies",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Financial institutes IBRD, IFC and IDA, all belong to the",
    options: ["IMF", "Commonwealth", "The World Bank", "None of the above"],
    answer: "The World Bank",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What has gathered strength in international business in the last decade is its",
    options: ["New concept", "Volume", "Investment", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Volume",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ today is the manufacturing center of the world and India its information technology hub.",
    options: ["China", "Brazil", "Japan", "None of the above"],
    answer: "China",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Successful companies plan their staffing needs to _______ their expansion plans.",
    options: ["Precede", "Follow", "Coincide with", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Coincide with",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Initially ______ currency was the benchmark in international business.",
    options: [
      "British Sterling Pound",
      "US Dollar",
      "Japanese Yen",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "British Sterling Pound",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Today many currencies are still pegged to ____ for their exchange rate.",
    options: [
      "British Sterling Pound",
      "US Dollar",
      "Japanese Yen",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "US Dollar",
    chapter: 1,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "International Financial ______ is concerned with how individual economic units, especially MNCs, cope with complex financial environment of international business.",
    options: ["Economics", "Market", "Management", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Management",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "International _________ is concerned with international financial / investment instruments.",
    options: [
      "Economics",
      "Financial market",
      "Management",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Financial market",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Foreign exchange rates are influenced by several factors in the international market like",
    options: [
      "Total domestic consumption",
      "Net disinvestment",
      "Gross Domestic Product",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Gross Domestic Product",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ represents the difference between imports and exports of tangible goods.",
    options: [
      "Balance of Payments",
      "Trade balance",
      "Exchange reserve",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Trade balance",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Inflation _______ purchasing power of the currency.",
    options: ["Increases", "Creates", "Reduces", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Reduces",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In most countries the most widely followed measure of inflation is the",
    options: ["COP", "BOP", "CPI", "All of the above"],
    answer: "CPI",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The _______ of the country participates in the local foreign exchange market by way of intervention to stabilize the exchange rate.",
    options: [
      "Finance ministry",
      "Treasury office",
      "Centralbank",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Centralbank",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "More than _____ of the activity in international foreign exchange market represents speculative activity.",
    options: ["90%", "50%", "30%", "None of the above"],
    answer: "90%",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The balance of payments is a ______ statement that summarizes transactions between residents and non-residents during a period.",
    options: ["Bi-Annual", "Financial", "Statistical", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Statistical",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Purchase or sale of goods or services in return for goods or services – a barter transactioninvolves",
    options: [
      "Two real transfers",
      "One real and one financial transfer",
      "Two financial transfers",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Two real transfers",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Balance of payments is statistical record of ______ arranged by one country to others.",
    options: ["Payments", "Receipts", "Both of the above", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Both of the above",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Imports and exports form ________ part of the balance of payments.",
    options: [
      "Current account",
      "Change in reserves",
      "Capital account",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Current account",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Transactions that effectivelyrepresent current and capital account activity are ________ transactions in the BOP.",
    options: ["Accommodating", "Autonomous", "Extraneous", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Autonomous",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Transactions undertaken by the Central Bank are ________ transactions in the BOP.",
    options: ["Accommodating", "Autonomous", "Extraneous", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Accommodating",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Demand deposit accounts, denominated in foreign currencies maintained by domestic banks with banks overseas are called _______ accounts.",
    options: ["VOSTRO", "LORO", "NOSTRO", "None of the above"],
    answer: "NOSTRO",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Demand deposit accounts, denominated in domestic currency maintained by overseas banks with domestic banks are called VOSTRO accounts.",
    options: ["VOSTRO", "LORO", "NOSTRO", "None of the above"],
    answer: "VOSTRO",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Foreign Exchange Marketis a_________ connected network of international banks, brokers and service providers.",
    options: [
      "Internally",
      "Electronically",
      "Internationally",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Electronically",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Four main areas through which monetary resources are raised include international equity market, debt market, _______ and trade deficit.",
    options: [
      "Cash market",
      "Loan syndication",
      "Debt building",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Loan syndication",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Two additional variables in raising finance internationally beyond those applicable to raising resources domestically are exchange rate and applicable ____ rates.",
    options: ["Inflation", "Intra-day", "Interest", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Interest",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Transfer of efficiency from one geographical area to another is the result of international",
    options: ["Trade", "Finance", "Travel", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Trade",
    chapter: 2,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Typical government control on foreign exchange is reflected in banning _____ from possessing foreign currencies.",
    options: ["Banks", "Locals", "Non-residents", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Locals",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Today this foreign exchange control exists in various degrees in _______ countries.",
    options: ["Very few", "Ten", "Different", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Different",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exchange controls are usually maintained in the belief that they help to ______ a country’s currency and its foreign exchange reserves.",
    options: ["Protect", "Weaken", "Weaken", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Protect",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "The origin of foreign exchange control can be traced back to",
    options: ["1990s", "1960s", "1930s.", "All of the above"],
    answer: "1930s.",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under exchange control regime all types of international transactions involving foreign exchange are",
    options: [
      "Nationalized",
      "Centralized",
      "Converted to local currency",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Centralized",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under exchange control, exporters have to deposit ____ of foreign exchange earned through exports.",
    options: ["Half of", "Some", "All", "All of the above"],
    answer: "All",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Local currency is undervalued in exchange control exercise in an attempt to",
    options: [
      "Curb inflation",
      "Cure depression",
      "Maintain exchange reserve",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Cure depression",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "With exchange control country regulates capital movement in order to prevent the flight of capital",
    options: [
      "Into the country",
      "Altogether",
      "From the country",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "From the country",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Through exchange control, a country tries to ______ international economic crisis.",
    options: [
      "Participate in",
      "Be responsible for",
      "Escape from abuses of",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Escape from abuses of",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exchange controls normally _______ economic cooperation internationally.",
    options: ["Facilitates", "Causes", "Obstructs", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Obstructs",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Exchange control is _________ for free flow of capital movement and investment.",
    options: [
      "Also not conducive",
      "Meant",
      "Is many times resorted to",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Also not conducive",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In India, exchange controls were first introduced in 1939 by the Government of India and ____ was empowered to administer it.",
    options: [
      "Ministry of Finance",
      "State Bank of India",
      "Reserve Bank of india",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Reserve Bank of india",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Exchange control in India is now regulated by",
    options: [
      "Foreign Exchange Management Act",
      "Defense of India Rules",
      "Foreign Exchange Regulation Act",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Foreign Exchange Management Act",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Selected banks are authorized by the RBI to deal in\nforeign exchange and they are known as",
    options: [
      "Exchange Brokers",
      "Exchange Dealers",
      "Authorized Dealers",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Authorized Dealers",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Government of India enacted the _____ act in 2002 to prevent entry of unlawful money into India.",
    options: [
      "Money Laundering Prevention Act",
      "Foreign Exchange Management Act",
      "Foreign Exchange Regulation Act",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Money Laundering Prevention Act",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If you compare FEMA with earlier FERA, you will observe that FEMA is more",
    options: ["Complex", "Liberal", "Comprehensive", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Liberal",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "The largest foreign exchange market in the world is located in",
    options: ["London", "New York", "Tokyo", "None of the above"],
    answer: "London",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ exchange rates are determined for each major transaction in the international market.",
    options: ["Card", "Master", "Ready", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Ready",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Merchant transactions are conducted at merchant rates which are quoted to nearest",
    options: [
      "0.0025 paisa",
      "0.0005 paisa",
      "Either of the two above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "0.0025 paisa",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Interbank foreign exchange transactions are governed by",
    options: [
      "Exchange Control Regulations of RBI",
      "RBI rules & guidelines of FEDAI",
      "State Bank of India",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "RBI rules & guidelines of FEDAI",
    chapter: 3,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The responsibility for accreditation of foreign exchange brokers and periodic review of their operations rests with",
    options: ["RBI", "FEDAI", "SBI", "None of the above"],
    answer: "FEDAI",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In March 1992, India adopted a dual exchange rate system called LERMS, under the scheme exporters are allowed to sell up to   ____ of their earnings in open market.",
    options: ["60%", "50%", "40%", "None of the above"],
    answer: "60%",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the regime of currency convertibility, a country becomes susceptible to international _____.",
    options: ["Ready", "Spot", "Hot", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Hot",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ assures international investors about being able to exit their investments without any restrictions.",
    options: ["FEMA", "Currency convertibility", "FERA", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Currency convertibility",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "FEDAI is a legally constituted association of",
    options: ["Banks", "Dealers", "Agents", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Banks",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Powers for implementing regulations under Foreign Exchange Management Act, 1999 (FEMA)rest with",
    options: [
      "The Ministry of Commerce",
      "The Reserve bank of India",
      "The Ministry of Industry",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "The Reserve bank of India",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Reserve Bank provides licenses to _____ categories of persons to transact with public at different levels.",
    options: ["Six", "Five", "Three", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Three",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ are permitted to undertake all categories of transactions pertaining to both Current and Capital accounts of the Balance of Payments.",
    options: [
      "Authorized Dealers",
      "Authorized Money Changers",
      "Offshore Banking Units",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Authorized Dealers",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ are permitted only to undertake both sale and purchase of foreign exchange.",
    options: [
      "Authorized Dealers",
      "Full Fledged Money Changers",
      "Offshore Banking Units",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Full Fledged Money Changers",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ are allowed to undertake banking operations only in designated foreign currencies essentially with non-residents.",
    options: [
      "Authorized Dealers",
      "Full Fledged Money Changers",
      "Offshore Banking Units",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Offshore Banking Units",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Foreign exchange is a scarce commodity; hence the Indian Government wants to ____ it.",
    options: ["Put a ceiling on", "Control", "Manage", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Manage",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In retail foreign exchange market, end users approach ______ for their requirements.",
    options: [
      "Authorized Dealers",
      "Authorized Money Changers",
      "Offshore Banking Units",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Authorized Dealers",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The committed rates quoted by authorized dealers for foreign exchange transactions are termed ____ rates.",
    options: ["Inter-bank", "Trade", "Merchant", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Merchant",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Tariffs and commissions charged by authorized dealers are maintained as per _______ regulations.",
    options: ["RBI", "FEMA", "FEDAI", "All of the above"],
    answer: "FEDAI",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Foreign exchange transactions in the wholesale market are carried by ______ at interbank rates.",
    options: [
      "Authorized Dealers",
      "Authorized Money Changers",
      "Offshore Banking Units",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Authorized Dealers",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Brokers are not allowed to operate in ______ foreign exchange market.",
    options: [
      "Retail",
      "Wholesale",
      "Both retail and wholesale",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Retail",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Capital account convertibility in foreign exchange was recommended by a committee headed by the Deputy Governor of RBI in 1997",
    options: [
      "And recommendations were accepted",
      "And recommendations were implemented",
      "But recommendations could not be implemented",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "But recommendations could not be implemented",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "As a part of liberalization of Exchange Control in India, individual residents are now permitted to invest up to _____ in international securities.",
    options: ["$ 100,000", "$ 50,000", "$ 10,000", "All of the above"],
    answer: "$ 100,000",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "At present Indian Rupee is fully convertible for _____ account transactions.",
    options: ["Current", "Capital", "GBP Capital", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Current",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The FEDAI was set up in 1958 as an association of banks dealing in foreign exchange under.",
    options: [
      "Companies Act 1956",
      "FEMA 1999",
      "FERA 1947",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Companies Act 1956",
    chapter: 4,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A foreign exchange rate, therefore, represents the value of the ____ currency expressed in terms of the variable currency.",
    options: ["Fixed", "Base", "Local", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Base",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A foreign exchange rate which provides a relationship between _____ currencies is called a cross currency rate.",
    options: [
      "Local and foreign",
      "Foreign and domestic",
      "Two non-domestic",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Two non-domestic",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An example of _____ rate in India would be I USD = INR 54.3825 – 54.3875",
    options: ["Adirect", "An indirect", "Cross currency", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Adirect",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The LHS rate in quotation is called ____ rate and represents the rate at which the bank would buy one unit of the base currency.",
    options: ["Offer", "Bid", "Ask", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Bid",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ the difference between the ASK and the BID rates, in a given quotation is called",
    options: ["Margin", "Cover", "Spread", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Spread",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "In ____ exchange rates vehicle currency gets eliminated.",
    options: ["ASK", "BID", "CROSS", "All of the above"],
    answer: "CROSS",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "GBP/USD 1.9693 – 1.9708 is a direct quotation in",
    options: [
      "The US",
      "Great Britain",
      "Both of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "The US",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "CHF/USD 0.7300 – 0.7306 is an indirect quotation in",
    options: [
      "The USA",
      "Switzerland",
      "Any one of the above",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Switzerland",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Identification of a country in ______ form is done by identifying country of variable currency.",
    options: ["Cross", "Indirect", "Direct", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Direct",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "PIPs or POINTS represent the ____ decimal place of a conventionally expressed exchange rate.",
    options: ["Last", "First", "Third", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Last",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "PIPS / POINTS represent the _____ increase / decrease in the rate.",
    options: ["Smallest", "Highest", "Normal", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Smallest",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A ‘Basis Point’ can be defined as the last decimal of a conventionally written _____ rate.",
    options: ["Bid", "Cross", "Interest", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Interest",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Arbitrage can be defined as an operation which involves simultaneous purchase and sale of ____ quantity of acurrency.",
    options: ["Equal", "Normal", "Pre-determined", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Equal",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Arbitrageurs only utilize quotations made by ____ and profit from them.",
    options: ["Others", "Central bank", "Them", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Others",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "There are _____ arbitrage possibilities in a perfect market.",
    options: ["No", "Limited", "Numerous", "None of the above"],
    answer: "No",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "The volume of arbitrage operations depends on the",
    options: [
      "Assessment capability of arbitrageur",
      "Opportunities provided by the market",
      "Errors in the exchange rates",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Opportunities provided by the market",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Bulls always anticipate ______ in the currency.",
    options: ["An appreciation", "A fall", "Fluctuations", "None of the above"],
    answer: "An appreciation",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bears require ______ resources for their activity (to first sell).",
    options: ["Stable", "Monetary", "Commodity", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Commodity",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "There is a conscious acceptance of risk in",
    options: [
      "Arbitrage",
      "Speculation",
      "Both of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Speculation",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In spot transactions settlement has to be arranged ______ contract date.",
    options: [
      "On 2nd working day after the",
      "On the",
      "On 3rd  working day after the",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "On 2nd working day after the",
    chapter: 5,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In order to calculate forward rate ‘n’ months forward, you need to know interest rate prevailing on   ______ currency",
    options: ["Variable", "Base", "Both of the above", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Both of the above",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Difference between a spot rate and forward rate of a currency is caused by ________ rates.",
    options: [
      "Fluctuations in exchange",
      "Changes in base currency",
      "Prevailing interest",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Prevailing interest",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If 1EUR = USD 1.3485 spot, and USD 1.3502 two months forward, you must know _____ rate to arrive at EUR interest rate.",
    options: [
      "USD interest rate",
      "EUR spot",
      "USD two months forward",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "USD interest rate",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When swap points are negative, they represent ______ on base currency.",
    options: ["Premium", "Discount", "Interest", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Discount",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "For ‘bid side’ swap points use _____ rate of Variable currency.",
    options: ["Margin", "Lending", "Deposit", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Deposit",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "For ‘bid  side’ swap points use ______ rate of Base currency",
    options: ["Margin", "Lending", "Deposit", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Lending",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "For ‘ask side’ swap points use _____ rate of Variable currency.",
    options: ["Margin", "Lending", "Deposit", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Lending",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "For ‘ask  side’ swap points use ______ rate of Base currency",
    options: ["Margin", "Lending", "Deposit", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Deposit",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In all _____ situations the swap points [forward margins] are always in descending order. [Left to Right]",
    options: ["Premium", "Discount", "Spot", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Discount",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It is understood that factors in ___________order, \nLeft to right, are positive (premium on base currency).",
    options: [
      "Ascending",
      "Descending",
      "Any one of the above",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Ascending",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a given schedule of forward margins if, LHS factors are _______ the RHS factors, they represent premium on base currency.",
    options: ["Less than", "Equal to", "More than", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Less than",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a given schedule of forward margins if, LHS factors are _______ the RHS factors, they represent discount on base currency.",
    options: ["Less than", "Equal to", "More than", "None of the above"],
    answer: "More than",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a given schedule of forward margin, LHS factors are added or subtracted to the ____ rate in the spot quotation.",
    options: ["Bid", "Spot", "Ask", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Bid",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a given schedule of forward margin, RHS factors are added or subtracted to the ____ rate in the spot quotation.",
    options: ["Bid", "Spot", "Ask", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Ask",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In premium situations forward margins are calculated to the ____ day of the calendar month.",
    options: ["Last", "First", "15th", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Last",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If AFM is negative, then it means that Rv &gt; Rb which means that the base currency would be at a",
    options: ["Premium", "Discount", "Minimum", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Discount",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Therate of change in the spot rate between two currencies is equal to the difference in their _____ rates.",
    options: ["Interest", "Forward", "Arbitrage", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Interest",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When interest rates are provided on two way basis[5.65% – 5.90%] the LHS rate represents the ____ rate.",
    options: ["Lending", "Bank", "Deposit", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Deposit",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The “carry” of an asset can be described as the difference between the appreciation in the asset (from purchase to sale date) and the ____ the asset.",
    options: [
      "Cost of acquiring",
      "Cost of holding",
      "Sale price of",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Cost of holding",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "A Carry trade transaction is",
    options: [
      "Double speculation",
      "An arbitrage",
      "Simultaneous buy / sell deal",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Double speculation",
    chapter: 6,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Special Drawing Rights (SDRs) are an international reserve asset created by the IMF are also known as",
    options: ["Paper Gold", "Euros", "EEC currency", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Paper Gold",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Value of Special Drawing Rights (SDRs) issued by IMF is usually expressed in",
    options: ["USD", "GBP", "JPY", "None of the above"],
    answer: "USD",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under the ‘pegged’ exchange rate system the central bank of a country pegs (fixes the value of) the domestic currency to",
    options: [
      "A basket of foreign currencies",
      "Bullion",
      "SDRs",
      "Anyone of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Anyone of the above",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Only one major economy currently uses the fixed exchange rate system, and that is",
    options: ["China", "Russia", "Australia", "All of the above"],
    answer: "China",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ Exchange Rate System has lower operating costs and is easier for importers and exporters.",
    options: ["Flexible", "IMF’s", "Fixed", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Fixed",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Indian Rupee belongs to",
    options: [
      "Currencies subject to Managed Float",
      "Freely floating currencies",
      "Pegged currencies",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Currencies subject to Managed Float",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "______ reflect the true economic fundamentals of the currency.",
    options: [
      "Currencies subject to Managed Float",
      "Freely floating currencies",
      "Pegged currencies",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Freely floating currencies",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ expose the country’s currency to speculative pressures and lead to its destabilization.",
    options: [
      "Currencies subject to Managed Float",
      "Freely floating currencies",
      "Pegged currencies",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Freely floating currencies",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Central Bank Intervention/Currency Interventionto guide exchange rate can take the form of _____intervention.",
    options: [
      "Securities Market",
      "Money Market",
      "Active",
      "Anyone of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Anyone of the above",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ combines the best features of the fixed &amp; variable exchange rates.",
    options: [
      "IMF’s exchange rate",
      "Managed or Dirty Float",
      "Pegged currency system",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Managed or Dirty Float",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Crawling Peg System relies heavily on",
    options: [
      "Purchasing Power Theory",
      "Frequent market interventions",
      "SDRs",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Purchasing Power Theory",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ provided for valuation of currencies against US $ on fixed basis.",
    options: [
      "Gold Standard",
      "Barter System",
      "Bretton Woods Conference",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Bretton Woods Conference",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Gold Standard was the first universally implemented exchange rate system. It was promoted by",
    options: [
      "Federal Bank of USA",
      "The UNO",
      "Bank of England",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Bank of England",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "The Gold Standard had to be ultimately abandoned as",
    options: [
      "Members did not restrict money supply to gold reserves",
      "Price of Gold started falling",
      "Countries with trade surplus were unhappy with the system",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Members did not restrict money supply to gold reserves",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "_____ is also known as IMF’s exchange rate system.",
    options: [
      "Gold Standard",
      "Flexible Exchange Rate System",
      "Bretton Woods System",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Bretton Woods System",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under _______ effectively, each currency was redeemablein US dollars, and US dollars were redeemable in gold.",
    options: [
      "IMF’s Exchange Rate system",
      "Gold Standard",
      "Pegged Exchange Rate system",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "IMF’s Exchange Rate system",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bretton Woods System allowed for devaluation of currency to correct structural imbalance in consultation with _____",
    options: [
      "Member’s Central bank",
      "IMF",
      "Bank of England",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "IMF",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "One main reason for failure of Bretton Woods System was",
    options: [
      "Its flexibility",
      "US could not devalue its currency",
      "BOP surplus of the US",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "US could not devalue its currency",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Under Smithsonian Agreement signed by G 10 countries, value of US Dollar was revised from $ 35 per ounce of gold to _____ per ounce.",
    options: ["US $ 43", "US $45", "US $ 38", "None of the above"],
    answer: "US $ 38",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The member countries of (EEC) voluntarily accepted a smaller variation zone from parity rate of (+/-) 1.125% for their currencies. This was termed",
    options: ["EEC tunnel", "EEC snake", "EEC lane", "All of the above"],
    answer: "EEC snake",
    chapter: 7,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Eurocurrency  is not to be confused with",
    options: [
      "Loans in various currencies",
      "Deposits in various currencies",
      "A currency",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "A currency",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_____ was one of the factors Contributing towards Growth of Euro \tCurrency (offshore) Market.",
    options: [
      "Falling value of the US dollar",
      "Strong dollar",
      "US ceiling on interest payable on bank deposits",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "US ceiling on interest payable on bank deposits",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "European banks were ______   reserve requirements on Euro-Dollar deposits.",
    options: [
      "Not subject to",
      "Subject to higher",
      "Subject to lower",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Not subject to",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "There was mandatory regulation on all banks in ______ to insure deposits accepted by them from public.",
    options: ["Europe", "Germany", "The US", "All of the above"],
    answer: "The US",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "_______ period of time of Eurocurrency loansleads to asset-liability mismatch problems for the banks.",
    options: ["Longer", "Uncertain", "Shorter", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Longer",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "It is observed that transactions on Eurocurrency markets are",
    options: [
      "Of retail nature",
      "Largely wholesale",
      "Numerous",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Largely wholesale",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Transactions in Eurocurrency market are focused upon London. London boasts of around ___of the total market.",
    options: ["66%", "One third", "One half", "None of the above"],
    answer: "One third",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Euro-credits are always given on a floating rate basis and are rolled over normally on ___ basis; interest rate is reviewed / reset after ___ months.",
    options: [
      "Quarterly ; three",
      "Six monthly ; six",
      "Annual ; twelve",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Six monthly ; six",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Straight Debt Bonds have ____ maturity and ____ coupon rates.",
    options: ["Variable", "Fixed", "Short", "Anyone of the above"],
    answer: "Fixed",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Floating Rate Notes (FRNs) are issued with maturity period varying from _____ years and their rates are linked to six months LIBOR rates.",
    options: ["5 – 7", "25 – 50", "10 years onwards", "None of the above"],
    answer: "5 – 7",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "____ ensure that the liability of the issuer is progressively reduced.",
    options: [
      "Sinking Fund Bonds",
      "Zero Coupon Bonds",
      "Deep Discount Bonds",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Sinking Fund Bonds",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Junk bonds carry coupon rates of at least ¬______ the normal rates.",
    options: ["3 – 4% above", "3 – 4% below", "Twice", "None of the above"],
    answer: "3 – 4% above",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "With _____ investor earns capital gains instead of interest income.",
    options: [
      "Sinking Fund Bonds",
      "Zero Coupon Bonds",
      "Deep Discount Bonds",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Zero Coupon Bonds",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Pound denominated bonds issued in the United Kingdom domestic markets by the foreign (non-UK) companies are known as ____ bonds.",
    options: ["Maple", "Matador", "Bull Dog", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Bull Dog",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Rembrandt Bonds are denominated in",
    options: [
      "Euros",
      "Chinese renminbi",
      "Australian Dollar",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Euros",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Commercial paper can be issued by borrowers with ____ credit rating.",
    options: ["Normal", "Excellent", "Below average", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Excellent",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______works on the principle of risk spreading and benefits the lenders as well as borrowers.",
    options: [
      "Corporatization",
      "Syndication",
      "Organization",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Syndication",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "The country ____ is not considered as a tax haven.",
    options: ["Panama", "Switzerland", "Bahamas", "Somalia"],
    answer: "Somalia",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "SIBOR stands for Singapore Interbank Offered Rate and its use is more common in _____ region.",
    options: ["American", "Asian", "European", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Asian",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Eurocurrency market functions on ___ rates.",
    options: ["Interest", "Exchange", "Margin", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Interest",
    chapter: 8,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Between the quotation to the customer and covering of the transaction, adverse exchange rate movement may result in loss. This risk is called _____ risk.",
    options: ["Translational", "Transaction", "Economic", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Transaction",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "‘Open Position risk’ is a typical case of ____ risk.",
    options: ["Translational", "Transaction", "Economic", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Transaction",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Exposure Netting is one more method of -",
    options: [
      "External hedging",
      "Exposure control",
      "Internal hedging",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Internal hedging",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The exchange risk can be completely avoided if the transaction is denominated in ____ currency.",
    options: ["Local", "Global", "Fixed", "Anyone of the above"],
    answer: "Local",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Foreign Currency account is one more method of",
    options: [
      "External hedging",
      "Exposure control",
      "Internal hedging",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Internal hedging",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "_____ cannot form a part of internal hedging.",
    options: [
      "Derivatives",
      "Exposure netting",
      "Leads and lags",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Derivatives",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "“A transaction or a financial instrument which receives its value through some other asset or security” is termed",
    options: ["Hedging", "Exposure control", "Derivative", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Derivative",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The gross volume of the transaction which is subject to risk is termed",
    options: [
      "Uncertainty of the future",
      "Variability of potential outcome",
      "Exposure",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Exposure",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "_____is normally calculated in terms of foreign currency.",
    options: ["Speculation", "Risk", "Exposure", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Exposure",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "________ should and can be controlled or managed through appropriate hedging transaction.",
    options: ["Risk", "Exposure", "Speculation", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Risk",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "There are three types of Risks;          Transaction Risk, Translational Risk and     Economic Risk. The ___ one is most common",
    options: ["First", "Second", "Third", "None of the above"],
    answer: "First",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "There are three types of Risks;          Transaction Risk, Translational Risk and     Economic Risk. ______ one is a managerial concept.",
    options: ["First", "Second", "Third", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Third",
    chapter: 10,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "History of international institutions starts with _______ which was established in 1930.",
    options: [
      "European Central Bank",
      "Bank for International Settlement",
      "International Development Association",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Bank for International Settlement",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "There was demand for liquidation of Bank for International Settlement due to its",
    options: [
      "Failure to show results",
      "Inappropriate working during the World War II",
      "Exhaustion of all reserves",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Inappropriate working during the World War II",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To make banking operations safer for customers and reduce risk of technical insolvency, banks are required to set aside a proportion of their",
    options: [
      "Capital unutilized.",
      "Annual profits in reserves",
      "Deposits as ‘reserve’",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Deposits as ‘reserve’",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Bank for International Settlement is an international organization of ______ banks.",
    options: ["Central", "Commercial", "Foreign exchange", "Foreign exchange"],
    answer: "Central",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ played a central role in establishing the Basel Capital Accords of 1988 &amp; 2004.",
    options: [
      "IMF",
      "Bank for International Settlement",
      "International Development Association",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Bank for International Settlement",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "Basel 1 accord of 1988 focused only on member banks’ ____ risk.",
    options: ["Market", "Credit", "Deposit", "All of the above"],
    answer: "Credit",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Basel I accord of 1988 focused mainly on ______ of its member banks.",
    options: [
      "Financial assets",
      "Capital adequacy",
      "Risk weighting",
      "All of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Capital adequacy",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Basel I Accord was______ development of financial conglomerates, financial innovation and risk management.",
    options: [
      "Was able to address",
      "Failed to address",
      "Structured on",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Failed to address",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "___ Accord aimed at consistent regulations for member banks to eliminate competitive inequality amongst internationally active banks.",
    options: ["Basel I", "Basel II", "Basel III", "Anyone of the above"],
    answer: "Basel II",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question: "_________ GDP annual growth.",
    options: [
      "Decrease",
      "Marginally increase",
      "Have no impact on",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "Decrease",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Basel III requirements will increase the incentives of banks to build",
    options: [
      "Capital reserves",
      "The regulatory framework",
      "Credit weighting mechanism",
      "None of the above",
    ],
    answer: "The regulatory framework",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
  {
    question:
      "______ norms for the first time covered assessment of credit, market operational and residual  risks.",
    options: ["Basel II", "Basel I", "Basel III", "None of the above"],
    answer: "Basel II",
    chapter: 11,
    isAnswered: false,
    isFlagged: false,
    marks: 1,
    selectedAnswer: "",
  },
];
